The first step in cleaning data programmatically which is
编程式数据清理的第一个步骤
a subprocess of data wrangling is defining what we want to clean.
是数据整理的一个子过程 即定义我们想要清理的内容
This is like creating a cleaning plan or instruction list.
这一点类似于创建一份清理计划或指示清单
This can also be thought of as pseudo code,
这也可以被视为伪代码
where we convert the notes we made in the assessed step like here,
在这里 我们把在这个评估步骤中所做的记录转化成
into specific cleaning tasks.
特定的清理任务
So we made three assessments previously.
所以 我们之前进行了三次评估
The missing values or NaNs,
丢失值或 NaN
the start date in consistencies for ASAP,
Startdate 中 ASAP 的不一致性
and also the non-descriptive column headers.
及非描述性列标题
We can't really do anything with the NaNs,
对于 NaN 我们真的无能为力
like we can't fill them in by finding missing information online or something.
我们不能通过网上或其他方式找到丢失的信息然后填写进去
The job posting simply just didn't have this stuff,
工作招聘并不包含这些信息
so let's just make a mental note of this and not write anything down here.
所以在这里 我们只是在心里记下它们 而不是记录下它们
We all have to be aware of these missing values when we start
我们需要在编码的时候知道有这些丢失值
coding because they can cause unintuitive results.
因为它们会造成不直观的结果
Okay, so we'll tackle the start date and consistencies first.
好的 我们首先处理 Startdate 的一致性问题
Again a reminder, these were multiple representations
再次提醒一下 这些是 Startdate 列中
of "as soon as possible" in the start date column,
“as soon as possible” 的多种表示方法
ASAP as soon as possible, even immediately.
ASAP、as soon as possible 甚至 immediately
And there are actually more you can't see here because Pandas automatically collapses,
在这里 实际上有更多内容是你看不到的 因为 Pandas 会自动折叠
some rows in this large data set.
大数据集中的一些行
There are a lot of these here.
这里有很多这种情况
So writing a script to minimize code repetition for the cleaning makes sense.
编写脚本 最大限度减少清理重复 这样才有意义
Let's pick ASAP as our standard.
我们挑选 ASAP 作为我们的标准
Okay, so here's one definition.
好的 这是一个定义
Select all records in the start date column that
选择所有在 Startdate 列中出现
have "as soon as possible," "immediately" etc.,
as soon as possible、 immediately 等的记录
and replace the text in those cells with "ASAP."
然后用 ASAP 替换这些单元格中的文本
And now, we'll define how we're going to fix these non-descriptive column headers.
现在 我们来定义如何才能解决非描述性列标题
This is a pretty small one off task that we
这是一项非常小的一次性任务
could do manually in a spreadsheet application or text editor,
我们可以在电子表格应用或文本编辑器中手动完成
but let's do it in Panda's.
我们现在在 Pandas 中进行吧
Again we'll define how we're going to fix this issue with code.
我们将再次定义一下如何利用代码来修复这个问题
Side note, we don't want spaces in the column headers because we can't
顺便说一句 我们不需要列标题中的空格
access columns using dot notation in Panda's if there are spaces.
因为如果有空格的话 我们不能使用 Pandas 中的点记法访问列
Dot notation means accessing columns in your data frame like so.
点记法是指像这样在DataFrame中访问列
If the actual start date column header had a space,
如果实际 Startdate 列标题中有空格的话
we wouldn't be able to do this.
我们就不能做到这一点
And we would only be able to access it using bracket notation.
我们只能利用括号记法访问